hello and welcome to this session on
auditing imp perview for business
Central as part of the business Central
lunch event for 2024 release Wave 2 um
today I'll go through auditing in
purview and the benefits it brings to
business Central pview is an auditing
solution that allows audit
administrators to see operations
executed by users across all Microsoft
services including business Central in a
single portal
this can help responding to security
events in case you want to see what a
user did for example after an account is
compromised um you can use it to run
forensic investigations and for
customers with specific business needs
or um industry compliance requirements
this can help them meet those
requirements in having user operations
uh be auditable let's jump straight into
a demo of what business Central events
in perview look like to reach pview you
navigate to pview microsoft.com and
you'll see this interface that allows
you to filter and search for specific
events across your
tenant in this case I'm looking for all
activities in business
Central and for that I can navigate for
to record type business
Central um and that would give me all
the events related to business Central
to find specific activities within
business Central I open this activity
Pane and filter specifically to dyamic
365 business Central and there you'll
see the categories of activities that we
have so if I'm only interested in
environment Administration activities i'
would ref filter in further to this of
course if I'm looking for more specific
events I can use the keyword search for
example to search for specific
environment name or I could use the user
filter to only return activities
undertaken by a specific
user finally what's important is to
select the date filter so let's say I'm
looking for all September month to dates
select that so once I'm happy I click
search I click refresh here and you can
see my search so the date filter the
activity name and the record type is
being queued and is running after a few
minutes this will complete and I can
open the report with more details where
I can see all events that met those
filters that were executed on this
tenant initially the events that you can
audit for business Cent for in prview
fall in these
categories um from environment
Administration that includes everything
you would do in the admin Center to
report Administration which include any
changes made to reporting in a business
sensor environment there are a few
things that are good to know um as we
enable auditing of business sensor
events in purview firstly auditing is
included and enabled by default with
most Microsoft 365 plans meaning that if
you have one of the included Microsoft
365 plans you don't have to do anything
to enable pview it's already running on
your
tenant by default pview retains the
locks for 180 days but by purchasing
add-on licenses or with specific
Microsoft 365 plans you can extend this
up to 10 years the easiest way to get to
pview events is in the pview portal
where you can run manual reports as I've
just shown you but for more advanced
needs you can use Powershell or the
management activity API to automate this
is only the beginning of auditing
business Central events in prview and
we'd really like to hear your ideas on
what else you would want to see in
purview for business Central to submit
your ideas never get to aka. ms/ BC
ideas and create a new
idea this concludes perview in business
Cal thank you for watching